okay welcome to week two of operation
get strong and sexy uh this is the third
training session
for uh
sammy and aaron
and it was a very very good training
session so first up
i want to show you some
mobility drills that i've been giving
sammy to work on her ankle mobility now
this left side looks a little bit worse
than a right side but i put the knee
close to the foot here
if the knees farther away it tends to
not be as good of a drill so get that
this
back knee close to this foot so it's
kind of more like a squat you're more
sitting over your your body
and um
anyway i i tell her to do this every day
and she's not very good at homework but
sami and aaron watch these videos so
this these videos are very good for them
to see
and hear my feedback so
the more often she does this and again i
think she gets further with this right
leg than her left leg but the more
frequently she does this the better is
the more effective it's going to be for
her i will also mention that uh i'll
pause it here this knee is coming out
pretty far over the foot
i've seen uh i've seen a lot worse
scenarios here but again our left side
looks a bit worse
and now here i'm going to pause it this
is a a kind of a motor control drill
i'm trying to teach sammy what it feels
like to
relax
and kind of put go into posterior pelvic
tilt and lumbar flexion and butt wink
and then what it feels like to arch she
needs to
learn and feel these lower erector
spinae muscles
contracting uh
keeping her pelvis in in a
in anterior tilt
and keeping that lumbar
extension
and also
when she when you do that your knees
will go forward which makes you realize
you need good ankle dorsiflexion so
i have her kind of relax and just go
real deep into a squat and then
go up into
into a neutral spine now she
she could use it maybe a little bit more
lordosis here but
it's their first week of learning this
so this
uh
now what's nice here is you see this
nice lumbar extension you can see she is
getting past parallel
now again this doesn't mimic a a squat
because she's holding onto a pull
if she had a bar on her back she'd
probably fall backwards she'd need to
lean a little bit more or
get more uh
dorsiflexion
but either way it's a good drill to
teach her the right muscles to do the
job so
i'm having her do this every day as well
so again she goes deep down into
flexion
and then
and she feels her muscles here she would
feel her erectors and everything and her
glutes and everything working to try and
hold this position so
so this is a good drill for her to learn
the right motor control and i i think
she has her mobility is not that bad she
has the raw materials to get good squat
depth without butt winking
um i think she just
she has super strong glutes and the
glutes work a little bit better when in
posterior pelvic tilt it's hard to keep
to the glutes work ideally and also
um
keep a good anterior tilt
so that's sami's problem and she doesn't
get hurt the way she squats either she
never has so
okay
now
i'm moving on to sumo deadlifts that was
the first exercise for the day
and uh this is the first time erin has
ever done them you can see she tries to
use the hips she doesn't sink down and
use the knees a lot but either way
this 135 is flying up for her
she's stronger in the sumo position we
didn't know that this is the first time
she's ever done sumo deadlifts
she gets five reps
uh
and now here's sammy
um
using 225
and um
she gets three reps here
sammy uh
this is a a pr for her but she just kind
of does a wide stance conventional
deadlift
those knees could go out more she could
keep the hips lower
but
um
i was trying to see she had done a
warm-up set and i was trying to
jump her up quick
here's aaron with uh
this is uh
and this is her
this is a one rep max for her actually
and then i have her do 135
for reps
she gets six reps
again and this time she
has a little bit better form
so
i think i'm gonna i'm gonna keep having
both girls do both conventional and sumo
because they both feed off each other
and it's really important to learn both
of them
uh initially
now um
aaron got a boo-boo on her saying we got
a booba on her knee
from uh
from doing her her uh
her sumo deadlifts
we have a video that we didn't record
okay now here's sammy learning front
squats
you can see she wins in pain it hurts
her shoulders this is a very knurled bar
you should be wearing a t-shirt when
front squatting
but
this is um
115 pounds
i wasn't sure what to expect
sami has a wide stance with sumo that's
okay you don't have to do narrow stance
sumo's you can do wide stance
now here's aaron moving on to close grip
bench
very good form this is her you know
her first time learning closed grip
and uh that's 85 pounds
um
now here is uh
sammy doing 135 pound front squat great
form and her butt wink is improving
she's not she's keeping that arch better
already already in her second week of
squatting
um
so she's a
very good at front squatting i was very
impressed that she could do 135
for reps
for very first time doing front squats
all right here's uh aaron again with
close grip bench
and this here is 85 pounds i'm trying to
work with her form
everything looks tight looks good
uh she lifts her butt off the bench see
there so that's not a true she does not
truly get 85 pounds but nevertheless
it's good to try heavier weight get
accustomed to it now here's sammy
learning close grip
and you can see she's trying to flare
the elbow so i'm trying to get her to
tuck
sammy has a lot of variability with her
bench in that uh
the bar will touch down at different
points each time over time as you gain
experience and proficiency with the
close grip bench or with any bench
variation you get better at lowering
that bar to the same point each time
but this is 65 pounds i like i really
like sammy's form here her leg drive
looks good or her um
keeps a good low back arch
over time she will become more stable
and not as loose that's something that
takes a while to learn keep in mind this
is her second time
uh really doing bench this way and this
is her first time doing close grip bench
um
now here's aaron
first time doing front squats i didn't
know what to expect
here she is using 65 pounds knee valgus
looks great here
uh and i could tell this was very easy
so
this was a very light load
so we went heavier next set
um
here's sammy again now here's 85 pound
close grip bench
looked great
looked easy because she used really good
form
she's a little bit wobbly
but uh
she gets three reps here
uh
wobbly but holds good position that's
not easy to do your first time learning
close grip bench so i was impressed
there now here's aaron with 85 pounds on
the front squat
again
looks easy little bit of knee knee
valgus especially with that right leg
comes in more
but uh
gets five reps
and gets really good depth on these
she's
she's not that far off from her her
conventional and her uh
front squats or her back squats and
front squats are very similar
so here's sammy trying a 95 pound she
just got 85 for three you think she
would get 95 but look at where she
lowers the bar and look at what watch
she
she um she doesn't get it so
anyway we um
she'll get that next week this is just
beginners learning
uh learning a new skill and since
they're gonna be competing in you know
five more weeks i want them to get
experience with one rep max's i don't
just want to do triples and and
you know sets of fives and threes
because they need to get experience
they're fast forwarding their progress
here now here's aaron with a
115 pound or is that 105 105 pound front
squat
uh she gets three two reps
nice came in a little bit we're working
on that
okay here's sammy again with 95 pounds
trying to tell
her uh
how to keep better position and then she
really
does not do well on this rep
um
but again this is why
you know getting strong takes time
getting i remember the first time i
learned close grip bench press my elbows
wanted a flare
so look how high she lowers it and then
she tries to adjust and then okay not
not working there
so
we switched uh
from close grip went to goblet squats
this is sammy's first time learning
goblet squats
trying to work on that butt wink
uh i just told her go deep and this is
lighter weight but try to keep that arch
but you can see she winks a lot
loses the curve
but
a lot of uh trainers have a lot of
confusion on this area well
there's a lot of lifters like um
like uh captain kirk he was a legendary
power lifter he had massive butt wink
when he squatted
but he never hurt himself he did that
his whole life
i suspect sammy's the same she could
probably do this her whole career and
and never have pain she's no she hasn't
hurt herself
but uh we're trying to work on it and i
think it's already improving
um especially on in week two of her
workouts
but nevertheless i think the goblet
squats are good for her you can see her
depth is kind of all over the place
sometimes she goes deeper sometimes not
as deep
but i'm i think i'm going to give her i
like giving them higher rep goblet
squats
for extra practice
now here's aaron with goblet squats it's
her first time doing them and she's
sinking on rock bottom and what i like
is aaron this prevents her from
collapsing in at the knees because i
tell her elbows have to go between her
legs so you can see uh
this is a great tool for aaron because
she
has the tendency to collapse i would
like to see her keep the torso a little
more upright and get the knees forward a
little more
but again first time learning goblet
squats it's okay we'll get better at
this
um
and then so i have them do the squats
bench and and or squats deadlifts and
bench press with high reps or sorry high
weight low reps
they don't get any metabolic stress from
doing these so now i'm having them do
higher up goblet squats
higher up hip thrust this is actually
245 pounds see those plates those are
100 pounders
so she got like six reps
um
and now here's sammy this is 295 it
doesn't look that heavy but those are
100 pound plates
see how hard it is for to get into
position
this is why i need to bring the hip
thruster with me i've been lazy and i
forgot it
next i told the girls to remind me to
bring the hip thruster
next week because uh just makes things
so much easier but this is sammy with
295.
i told her to get six to eight reps
she uses very good form
looks nice and smooth
uh
it looks like she's getting full range
sammy has a tendency to look to the
right
when she does these
um
anyway this was a very good set
i was very happy with it and then
again 245 pounds for erin this is the
heaviest she's done with hip thrust
and uh
her
she's already seeing results with her
glutes her glutes are already getting
more muscular
just from working with me the last month
um but
she's manhandling 245 pounds keep in
mind she weighs 100 so
and let's see this is again 295 for
sammy again
she keeps screwing up and
it's hard to get in position with this
setup we have
uh
with the hip thruster it's easy
but uh
let's see i think she's
off off balance here she doesn't like
this pad
um
but uh
so we get rid of that guy there and then
makes it easier for her
um
some people's feet slide on that wood
sammy doesn't though sammy keeps their
feet a little bit too close see that i
like the shins to be at a right angle
sammy's always kind of lifted like this
um
but this was kind of a worthless set see
that she just it's not a good set
terrible set there those 295 she's
sliding down her feet are falling
forwards
anyway kind of a worthless set we have
the hip thruster they'd all be good sets
but uh
we'll bring that next week now here's
aaron with a burnout
this is
135.
i can't remember how many she gets
but i'm doing this for to get the burn
to get the metabolic stress
oh she gets 20 reps yeah yeah so this is
a good good burn for erin
nice 20 rep set
aaron likes to hold it just shy of
lockout and i have to tell her squeeze
the glutes up a little higher when she
does these her butt burns incredibly bad
so this is good and now here's sammy
with 185
much better setup see how the shins are
more vertical this set
and uh she's in good position here so
she busts out 20 reps here
sammy hates high rep work just like me
i hate high reps but
sammy's very strong busts out 185 for
20.
with good form feet are in much better
position this time
vertical shins and it's much easier for
her
holds that lock out she's always been
good at lockout now i'm teaching them
bent over rose
this is the first time they're learning
bent over rose i really like the way
aaron doesn't see that back position
and i like doing better rose more more
with the torso more horizontal like that
and uh
out in front of the body more so sitting
back getting a good
good torque on the hips but with sami
it's hard for her to hold
hold that position now that is very good
position for sami because she she tends
to round so this is a great set for
sammy i was very happy with this ideally
i'd like her to be more horizontal but
this is as good as she can get
um
and then uh
here's eric this is a very good exercise
for aaron this um
torches her glutes and her glutes you
can feel when palpate or glutes when she
does these they get rock hard this is
one of her best exercise for tension
and for metabolic stress and it works
both her upper and lower
glutes um
and she's using two bands here a blue
and a green band and here's sammy using
two blue bands
uh
sammy it's weird sometimes she feels
these a ton if she gets into the right
position and sometimes she doesn't it's
just hit or miss and it has to do with
her see there she's burning really bad
she feels like her glutes are about to
pull but then other times she doesn't
even feel her glutes working much
yeah so this is a good exercise for
sammy
uh she just has to learn to do it in the
right position